Hike!
Martel!
Martel, you're a wimp!
I can't believe that.
Martel goes for a give-up slide.
-It did look cautious.
-I could have scored on that!
That could be the last play of the season.
In case you haven't heard,
the players' strike became official...
...at 4 p.m. Eastern time.
I'm sad that the players' demands,
which center around...
...a rise in the current salary cap,
have been rejected by the owners.
I have told my union brothers to walk.
Get me Jimmy McGinty!
Have him here tonight.
Yes, sir.
I'm here with Eddie Martel.
A lot of angry fans out there feel
that the players are being too greedy.
Anything you'd like to say?
Dwight, I know $5 million a year
sounds like a lot of money...
...but I have to pay 10 percent to my agent,
5 percent to my lawyer...
Do you know what insurance costs
on a Ferrari, mother...
Pat, back to you.
That was Washington running back
Malcolm Lamont.
It's all about money, folks,
but isn't it always?
Yes. This is Pat Summerall
for John Madden saying...
...so long from Nextel Stadium.
-You look like shit.
-I'm dying, Jimmy.
Come on.
You've been dying for 20 years.
-Give me a cigarette.
-I quit.
Nobody likes a quitter.
-See the game today?
-No.
Why, you liar.
Could you believe that slide by Martel?
What a pussy.
-What's up?
-Take a ride with me.
How's the wife?
She had her lips done.
I never even knew
you could have your lips done.
Looks like a largemouth bass.
I'm too old to screw around.
Let me give it to you straight.
I want you back.
-You already have a coach.
-I'll take care of it.
-Like you took care of me.
-Now, Jimmy...
Your players all flew home
to their castles...
...in their private jets.
We're gonna finish the season anyway.
I'm gonna use replacement players.
-Jeez, what a business.
-We've got four games left.
We win three, we're in the playoffs.
Really? Win three out of four
with replacement players?
That's not too much to ask.
You won for me once, you can do it again.
What's the matter, Jimmy?
Nobody's gonna give you
a better chance than this...
...after that Dallas mess.
-I was right about that.
-It had nothing to do with being right!
You went head-to-head
with an $8 million quarterback.
Who did you think was gonna win?
That's not gonna happen here!
I'm talking about a team
of poor nobodies who play to win...
...not a bunch of bitchy millionaires.
Come on, Jimmy!
I'm thinking.
Hello!
I want total control of my team.
I want to be able to recruit anybody
that I want, no interference.
My word is my bond.
I want it in writing.
Okay, Jimmy.
Okay.
We thought we'd skip
special teams for now.
It'll be tough enough
to put together a team in a week.
-We're gonna go a different way.
-A different way?
Here's a list of people
I've been watching over the years.
They've all played football,
not all of them in the pros.
But they all have something
unique to bring to the game.
We'll take them and try
to put together a winning team.
If nothing else,
they should be fun to watch.
Daniel Bateman, SWAT team officer.
Awarded a Purple Heart for losing
a kidney during the Gulf War.
A walk-on at Michigan State
before he gave up football...
...to sneak back into the service
for one more tour of duty.
Clifford Franklin.
Great attitude, great desire, and
the fastest son of a bitch I've ever seen.
Clifford! Twinkie!
What's up, man? Got any Twinkies?
Can he catch?
That's why I have you.
André and Jamal Jackson.
Together, these guys were the best
tandem team of guards in the game.
-You're kidding me!
-André got traded and they fell apart.
He ain't our problem no more.
We gonna play football.
-Football?
-Football.
Nigel Gruff.
Striker out of Cardiff,
now residing in HelI's Kitchen.
He's called "The Leg" because he can kick
a soccer ball the length of the field.
Gentlemen...
...the drinks are on the house!
Bollocks!
Pissing away our money again?
-No, the money's on the way.
-Where? To the OTB?
I got a winning horse!
I swear on my mom's grave!
Your mother's grave?
He's swearing on his mother's grave!
Nigel, listen. I want my money!
-Has he kept in shape?
-By Welsh standards.
Shane Falco.
Shane Falco?
"Footsteps" Falco from Ohio State?
The same.
-He hasn't played in years.
-Should be well rested then.
You look like a swordfish I caught once.
He hit the deck just like that.
-You know who I am?
-Yeah.
You're Jimmy McGinty.
That old coach from the '80s.
We met just before the Sugar Bowl.
I remember.
Hell of a game that Sugar Bowl.
-What'd you lose that by? 40 points?
-That would be 45.
Sometimes a game like that sticks
with you. You never shake it off.
-Got three concussions to prove it.
-That's why girls don't play.
Why are you here, coach?
I'm back with the Sentinels.
I want you to quarterback.
I found the best guards
and a wide receiver...
...even you couldn't overthrow.
-I'm retired.
-Retired?
It looks like things have gone
real well for you since.
I got no complaints.
It's quiet here.
Nobody bothers me.
That's the great thing about plankton,
it pretty much keeps to itself.
You know what separates the winners
from the losers?
The score.
Getting back up
after being kicked in the teeth.
I watched films of your games
since the Sugar Bowl.
You shouldn't have been trying
to carry the whole team that first year.
Your teammates leaned on you
and you crumbled.
-Is that how you want to be remembered?
-I don't want to be remembered at all.
You're young. lf you do well,
who knows what'll happen after the strike.
I'm not making you any promises,
but why don't you take a chance?
Rather than scraping crap
off the bottom of somebody else's toys.
Think it over.
You could be part of something.
I'm here to remind fans that what
the owners are doing is unconscionable.
They have blatantly hired scabs...
...which goes against our Constitution,
the Declaration of lndependence...
...and the Emancipation Proclamation.
Here come the scabs now!
That's Eddie Martel!
That's Wilson Carr!
Hey, Wilson!
I love you, man! What's happening?
I love you, man!
I'm gonna bust a cap in your ass,
and in your ass!
Piss off!
Get that bible out of here!
Sorry about this.
Put God in your heart!
I'm very sorry.
Get a job, you wankers!
Looking good out there!
You've got the goods!
Where did you learn to catch like that?
Roberts, make that D-back commit
before you cut, all right?
Jimmy.
-My tight end is deaf.
-Yeah, I know.
Jimmy, how am I gonna coach a deaf man?
You won't need to.
Brian Murphy would've gone
in the first round if he wasn't deaf.
Played college ball
here in D.C. at Gallaudet.
But I've got to be able
to communicate with him and how...
Learn to sign.
Horseshit!
Look at it this way,
he'll never be called offsides on an audible.
-Good to see you.
-You too.
-How are you?
-Good.
This is "The Leg"?
I thought you told me he was solid muscle.
He's much stronger than he looks.
I'm wiry.
Go get some kicks in.
He's "wiry."
"Wiry."
I'm sure you've been briefed
as to your situation.
Coach McGinty wanted you
with us for five weeks...
...and the Governor's complied.
Nice watch.
What?
This?
It's a fake.
Damn thing's always broken.
It's only right twice a day.
Why don't we join the others?
No sense standing here by ourselves...
...out of screaming distance.
-Come on, let's fire out of there!
-Jimmy.
-Falco, when's he coming?
-Relax, he'll be here.
Come on, quick feet!
I am relaxed, but that's not the point.
It's nervous energy.
Case in point:
We don't have a quarterback, do we?
-Fire out of there!
-We don't have a game plan for Sunday.
The only good thing I can say
about our one offensive weapon is...
...it's "wiry." What the shit is that?
No, no, it's "wiry."
-However the hell you say it!
-Say it: "Wiry."
"Wiry."
Holy! Look at this mamma-jamma!
Have you lost weight?
Coach, don't say that.
You look great.
Why don't you work out on SOD?
SOD.
-He's lost weight?
-Sumo wrestler.
Expert at pushing people around.
That's what pass blocking is, remember?
That's right.
Next one, 74. Come on!
Set, hut!
All right! Way to go!
It's all about pushing people around!
Set! Hut!
Come on, Sumo boy.
Let's see what you can do.
Set. Hut!
Yes! Good hit, Sumo boy!
Now get this off of me!
"That'll do, pig, that'll do."
-Screw you, cockroach.
-You'll have to find your dick first.
Get this off of me!
Hey, scab!
-I don't want any trouble.
-You hear that?
He's taking away my job,
but he doesn't want any trouble.
Not only is he taking your job,
he's taking your parking space too.
What's up?
Is that right, Falco?
I didn't know it was yours. I'll move it.
No, let us do that.
Guys, move the new boy's ride for him.
Coming right up, Mr. Falco.
Ready?
One. Two. Three.
Thanks, guys.
Asshole.
Jesus! "Footsteps" Falco.
They must be getting desperate.
Hey, Falco!
You're not even a has-been!
You're a never-was!
Go!
Come on, let's pick it up!
Form a line here! Let's go seven on seven.
Check it out, it's our new quarterback.
We're in business now.
You're late.
Car trouble.
You still got an arm?
Hey, Falco.
Go!
That's gonna leave a mark.
-Leo, Franklin's down again.
-I'm okay.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Let's play some football!
Danny Bateman.
Shane Falco.
Nice pop, Danny.
Thanks, coach.
In practice, we don't hit the fellows
with the red shirts on.
I know, but I see that red
and I just want to go after it like a bull.
Okay, Danny.
Huddle up!
Get used to setting up on the run.
Move fast, think even faster.
-You'll live longer.
-I'm very interested in that.
Huddle up!
Hey! Shane Falco.
I lost a ton of money
on that Sugar Bowl of yours.
What a bloody shambles that was.
You could smell the stink
all the way back in Wales.
Nice meeting you.
Ready!
Hut!
Shit! I forgot about the whole red
shirt thing! This game's confusing.
Remember...
...red means stop.
Like a streetlight, right?
-Yeah.
-Get on up.
Go ahead. I'm gonna lie here
a moment and collect my thoughts.
Work shit out, right?
-You should be glad he's on your side.
-Yeah.
-So you have a cheer or something?
-Are you ready?
"Let's hear it for the quarterback
Hey-hey, ho-ho
"Could anyone play better?
Say-say, no-no
"Tackle, tackle, tackle, tackle
Tack, tack, tack
"Show those others boys what they
lack, lack, lack
"lf I gave you a dollar
You could keep most of the change
"'Cause all I really want is a quarterback! "
"California oranges, Texas cactus
"We think your team needs a little practice
"Sit 'em in a highchair
Feed 'em with a spoon
"Roll 'em up in toilet paper
Kick 'em to the moon! "
-That was great, thank you.
-Thank you.
Can you dance?
Let me have some of that duck.
-What the hell is this?
-Chinese spareribs.
If you don't want it,
get the fuck out of here.
I'm trying to figure out
how the Chinaman over here...
...gets 700 pounds off of eating this shit.
I'm Japanese, not Chinese.
-Same difference.
-What?
It's the same difference!
All that big...
Nigger, please.
You do know Japan and China
are two different countries, right?
-You do know I got an atlas, bitch?
-Really, gangster?
Yeah.
We're on the same team!
We're on the same team! Now chill out!
-The mick's right.
-I'm not a mick! I'm bloody Welsh!
Whatever.
-I'm going to sit with the deaf kid!
-Jesus Christ!
Praise his glory, Nigel!
You praise his glory!
"Slash 'em, slash 'em
Cut 'em down
"Smear their blood all over town
"Punch 'em, hit 'em
Make it last
"Come on, boys, let's kick some ass! "
I played one game in the pros,
I blew out my knee and that was it.
Shit.
All I want to do is score one touchdown
before I hang up my pads. That's it.
You'll get it.
Hey, man.
Wilkinson! Earl Wilkinson!
I knew I recognized you, man! I knew it!
You played for Minnesota, baby!
Oh, shit! Earl Wilkinson, man!
Oh, my God!
You'd have been All-Pro
if you hadn't beat up them cops!
What I had meant to say was "allegedly"...
...allegedly beat up them cops
and because...
...a good Christian boy like you
would never do nothing like that!
That's right.
The way I heard it,
my man didn't even do nothing anyway!
Them cops were just jealous
of the black man.
Hear what I'm saying?
My boy's been living large!
I can't stand the cops!
I better not see a cop!
-I'll whup a cop's ass! Believe it!
-I'm a cop.
Look!
Bundt cake!
-Look at these yummy little monkeys!
-Hello!
Oh, hey.
Yeah.
-Are you Heather and Dawn?
-Yep, we sure are.
You don't know how excited I am...
...that I actually have some girls
with dance experience!
-I'm excited too!
-I know! Me too, too.
So, Heather, you were in Cats,
which is so terrific...
No, Pussycats.
You know, the club next to the airport?
Pussycats.
-That style of dancing would be...
-Is lap-dancing a style?
No. I mean...
Oh, my God, I forgot to tell you something.
What?
She always does that.
I've seen all I need to see.
No way! I'm so excited!
Go suit up.
-Go down the tunnel and to the left.
-Okay.
If you guys have any friends down
at the club, would you send them over?
-Sure.
-Yeah, absolutely.
Where are you going, Number 48?
I was watching you today.
You looked good.
Good release, strong arm.
You're gonna do fine.
Thanks.
I'm Annabelle Farrell.
-Shane Falco.
-I know.
I remember you
from the '96 Sugar Bowl game.
Didn't anybody have anything
better to do that day?
You should get some help
to turn this back over.
Yeah, I was thinking
I'd call AAA later or something.
-Do you want a lift?
-Yeah.
Yeah, that would be great. Thanks.
Why'd you stay in the pocket at practice?
I don't comment to quarterbacks
about style but...
...you need to keep scrambling
against Detroit, with Prescott back.
-Prescott hasn't crossed.
-He will on Sunday.
-It's a secret so you can't prepare.
-How do you know?
My friend's a cheerleader for Detroit.
She tipped me.
He's left-sided,
shotgun formation, roll right.
Van Gundy's on the right.
He's been All-Pro two years,
but one of my cheerleaders...
...is friends with a girl
who broke up with him.
He's been drinking ever since she left him.
He's hung over! He's a good second
slower off the snap than usual.
I'll stick to the right side.
Unless what they say
about Martinez is true.
-That was fun.
-This is great! You live out here?
Which one's yours?
Here. You see that white yacht
with the satellite dish?
I'm the old houseboat next to it,
covered in seagull shit.
What did you name her?
Phyxsius.
-Phyxsius, what does that mean?
-"Putting to flight."
You want to come onboard for a beer?
Nothing personal,
but I don't date football players.
I don't blame you.
Not even quarterbacks?
Especially not quarterbacks.
You guys are the biggest babies of all.
The biggest babies?
Yeah.
-Thanks for the ride.
-Good luck on Sunday.
-Be careful out there.
-I will.
Shane.
What's up?
Just...
...watching the game.
Nervous?
No.
I'm good.
Like a duck on a pond.
On the surface everything looks calm,
but...
...beneath the water, those feet
are churning a mile a minute.
You'll be fine.
Find a way to lead your team.
Earn their respect.
Yeah.
How are you doing?
Me?
I'm just another duck on the pond.
Coach, can I ask you a question?
-Yeah, shoot.
-Why me?
I look at you and I see two men...
...the man you are,
and the man you ought to be.
Someday, those two will meet.
Should make for a hell of a football player.
Get some sleep, kiddo.
You play professional football tomorrow.
Welcome to Nextel Stadium,
in our nation's capital.
I'm Pat Summerall and with me,
as always, is John Madden.
Detroit bought an entire semi-pro team
once the strike happened.
Washington is going with
a bunch of unknowns.
Although we'll see a few guys
we know today.
Like Shane Falco, that talented quarterback
who fell out of sight...
...after a disastrous showing
in the Sugar Bowl.
Having a little snacky-poo
before the game?
-It does the body good.
-You are one crazy son of a bitch.
-You know how I know that?
-How?
Only a crazy son of a bitch
would eat eggs before a game!
I need to bulk up.
-You want one?
-No!
It's good for you.
Sentinels, listen up.
Welcome to professional football.
Some will say
that your accomplishments...
...will soon be forgotten, you're not
real players, this isn't a real team.
And I say that is bullshit!
Because, as of today,
you're all professional football players.
You're being paid to play.
I want you to remember that because...
...the men whose places you've taken
forgot that a long time ago.
Bring it in here.
Bring it in, guys.
Let's play some football!
-D.C.
-All right!
For some of these players,
this is another shot...
...and a last shot for a guy like Falco.
Remember that beating he took
from Florida?
That's nothing compared to those beatings
he took in Seattle.
One thing we do know
is that Falco can take a hit.
Well, I'll tell you,
he's sure had a lot of practice at it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your Washington Sentinels!
-Did you see that?
-That's a pretty good hit.
Will the medical trainers
please report to the east tunnel?
Maybe he was a little overanxious, huh?
And now,
the rest of the Washington Sentinels.
Kick-off!
Not bad, let's go!
There can only be one leader
out there, all right? You be it.
-That's where I stand.
-No, it's not.
-That's my spot in the huddle.
-It's not.
-Get to your spot.
-Let's go, chopstick!
Let's play football! What do you say?
-It's my spot now!
-Not for long, you tub of rice shit!
What's the problem?
You can't do jack shit!
-Pork rice!
-I'm Japanese, not Chinese!
Don't mess with my brother.
What's going on?
Something seems to be going on
in the huddle.
Falco's on his back.
They haven't had a play yet
and Falco's down.
He got hit by his own guy! He was
looking out his earhole for a minute!
This isn't a good sign.
-Am I hurt already?
-Your partner knocked your head off.
Let's go.
Come on, get it together!
I'm the quarterback.
I'm the only one who talks in the huddle.
-But he was in my spot.
-I don't give a shit!
Now huddle up.
If you've got something to say,
raise your hand.
Is that understood?
Suppose you don't feel good,
or you're hurt.
Tell me before the huddle starts. Okay?
Okay, here we go.
DC Right, Switch, 25 Blast.
What?
-That's to the left?
-The right.
To the left!
Be quiet or they'll hear us, and then what?
Play game!
Number 16 on the offense! Five yards!
Well Pat, so far the Sentinels...
...have minus 10 yards offensively.
I've seen monkey-shit fights
at the zoo more organized than this!
DC Right, Pro, 424 Tomahawk,
on one, on one. Ready?
Ready?
I'm coming for you, Footsteps!
Green 22!
Hut! Hut!
Come on, Shane!
You could hear Falco's fillings
drop all the way up here!
Detroit takes over the football
with excellent field position.
Give me an S!
Give me an E!
Give me an N!
Give me a T!
Give me an..."
I! "
We'll get them next time.
Eagle over, cover four!
On three, get ready!
All day, blue eyes!
It's Christmas morning...
...and Santa's coming down the chimney!
I'm gonna bury your family!
I'm gonna bury your dog!
Champ, champ!
Now that's football!
You get it? You like it?
The Sentinels have set a record
for penalties in the first three minutes!
-We're still waiting for the stats on that.
-Personal foul!
Number 56 on the defense!
Half the distance to the goal!
Bateman on that one.
That was just a cheap shot.
-That should be worse than a penaIty.
-They're walking right through us!
Touchdown, Detroit!
Don't worry about it.
Let's go!
Double-slot Zag, okay?
-What?
-I don't feel too good.
-Suck it up.
-Come on!
Jesus Christ!
-Eggs!
-That's ripe!
What'd you eat, man?
If we don't move,
I'm going to blow chow, too.
We're in a huddle! Double-slot zag, 88...
Jesus!
Goddamn!
I tried to tell you, I can't be around
somebody puking or I start puking.
Shit.
Okay, okay!
On three...
...everyone move left. Ready?
Hut, hut, hut.
What the hell is that?
What?
John, how many years have we been
calling games together?
Nineteen, I think.
Ever seen anything like that?
Not on a football field.
-What are they doing?
-Beats me.
Look at it this way. It's the first thing
we've done together as a team.
-Hey!
-Clean it up! Let's go!
Break!
Ready? Blue 42!
Blue 42!
Hut!
First down, Washington.
-Was it out of bounds?
-Yes, on 23.
-Blue Right, 60, X Post.
-Blue Right, 60, X Post!
Let's go, let's go!
Go, from four. Hut!
Now we're rolling!
Signs of life from Washington here.
That last completion by Falco
puts them back in field-goal range.
-Field goal, let's go!
-Field goal.
Nigel.
It's over the bar, not under.
Okay? Go get 'em.
-Hold that.
-Here comes the field-goal team.
A 40-yard attempt for kicker Nigel Gruff,
against the wind.
Here's a guy from Wales,
and he's kicking his first field goal ever.
This is a tough distance.
Yeah, she's there! She's there!
-Boom! Boom!
-Nigel Gruff kicks and scores!
Halftime score: Washington 3, Detroit 14.
That's the second time
a Washington player has been...
-...knocked out by his own teammate.
-There's a rule in sports:
Don't do anything great if you can't handle
the congratulations.
-There is?
-Yup.
Give me an S!
Give me an E!
Give me an N!
Give me a T!
Give me a...
Watch the wheel!
All right, let's go!
Touchdown, Smith! That one gets
the Sentinels back into the game.
This guy is a heck of a player,
but I don't know him.
According to the Sentinels,
it says Ray Smith is...
That's weird!
No college given, no high school.
Just says he's been a resident
of the State of Maryland...
...for the last two years,
and he likes to embroider!
-He does some fancy work with the ball.
-Weird.
Ready!
Green 11!
Falco's sacked and the ball comes loose.
It's Detroit's ball
with only a minute remaining.
Let's go! Let's go!
Danny, Danny.
I need that ball. Get me the ball.
You need the ball.
-Get me the ball.
-The ball.
Are you gonna get me the ball?
I hope he doesn't kill somebody.
I'm back! I'm back!
Get the ball!
I got it!
Now that is all-Madden team!
-You're the man.
-I'm the man!
-You got me the ball.
-I got you the ball!
-Go sit down now, Danny.
-Okay.
-Number 56 recovers the ball.
-Falco!
We've gotta pass.
It's gotta be in the end zone.
DC Right, Zig, 90 Eagle. You can do this.
All right? Let's do it! Come on!
-Blue 25!
-Here comes the pain, baby!
Blue 25!
-Check!
-What are you doing?
Check!
Black 32!
-What?
-He's changing the play.
He's checking off the run.
I told him to pass!
Shit!
Falco calls an audible
at the line of scrimmage...
...and Cochran almost has a touchdown!
What a heartbreaker for Washington.
Final score: Washington 10, Detroit 14.
If I'd wanted Cochran to have that ball,
I'd have called it that way.
-I read blitz.
-Bullshit.
I put the game in your hands.
You got scared.
I read blitz.
Winners always want the ball
when the game's on the line.
WFAN, the Sports Fan's Show.
How do you feel about the strike?
The fans are getting screwed. I've got
season tickets I can't give away!
-What about the replacement players?
-They're nobodies.
"At first I was afraid
I was petrified
"Kept thinkin' I could never live
without you by my side
"But then I spent so many nights
Thinkin' how you did me wrong
"And I grew strong"
Why'd you play that dumb-ass song?
I put on The Commodores.
That shit just came on.
Can somebody please cut that bullshit off?
-We did the best we could do.
-You don't get points for trying.
Let's face it, boys,
we screwed the pooch today.
Hey, there they are!
Ladies and gentlemen...
...your Washington Sentinels!
He's the luckiest guy here. At least
he couldn't hear the booing today!
Hello! Anyone home? Did I hear an echo?
Where'd McGinty get Rain Man?
The Special Olympics?
No wonder they couldn't win.
He can't even order a drink!
-Iay off.
-Iighten up.
It's not like he can hear.
I can.
What's that say?
"One good thing about being deaf,
you can ignore the assholes."
You asshole.
That's funny.
It's cool!
You had enough?
You've got shit for brains,
but you've got balls.
Thank you.
Danny, remember what I told you
about red shirts in practice?
Yeah.
-Forget about it.
-Okay.
Martel.
Who's the man? Who's the man?
Come on! Come on!
Come on, come on! Stop!
Let's play football, bitch!
We are all God's children here!
"And deliver thee into the hands
of brutish men"...
Ezekiel 21 :31 .
This is some more bullshit!
It's more of a homecoming for you.
You gonna be a funny man?
Bateman! Wilkinson!
Come on, guys, what are you doing?
Can't we all just get along?
Come on.
Why are we the only ones in this jail?
-Simple. They're winners.
-Hell, no. Not tonight.
That was pretty sweet,
you sitting on Wilson's head, Jumbo.
Thanks, Jamal.
He wasn't the only one
who kicked ass tonight.
You're the man tonight, Clifford Franklin!
What?
You were hiding behind the jukebox.
Wasn't he?
At first, I admit, I was afraid.
-Shit, I was petrified.
-You were petrified?
"Thinkin' I could never live
without you by my side"
-The Lord is by your side.
-Have mercy.
"And then I spent so many nights
thinkin' how you did me wrong
"And I grew strong"
You know I hate this damn song.
"I learned how to get along
And so you're back
"from outer space
"I just walked in to find you here
with that sad look upon your face
"I should have changed that stupid lock
I should have made you leave your key
"If I'd have known for just one second
you'd be back to bother me
"Go on, now, go
"Walk out the door
"Just turn around now
'cause you're not welcome anymore"
Remember this?
"Weren't you the one
who tried to hurt me with goodbye?
"Did I crumble?
Did you think I'd lay down and die?
"Oh, no, not l
I will survive
"As long as I know how to love
I know I'll stay alive
"I've got all my life to live
I've got all my love to give
"And I'll survive
"I will survive
"Hey, hey!
"It took all the strength I had
not to fall apart
"Kept tryin' hard to mend the pieces
of my broken heart
"And I spent oh so many nights
Just feeling sorry for myself
"I used to cry
But now I hold my head up high
-"And you see me"
-Four, five!
Okay, all right.
Frankie.
If anything like this bar fight
happens again...
...there'll be no place
on the team for any of you.
-Do I make myself perfectly clear?
-Yes, sir.
Just for the record...
...l would've loved to have seen
Martel get his ass kicked.
Let's get out of here!
Hey, Shane.
What are you doing?
My job.
-You're a professional football player.
-Sure, this week.
When that's all over, you know...
...I'll be back here.
I don't want to lose my customers.
I was on my way to work.
Do you need a ride?
I'm good.
-I got my truck back.
-How is it?
Flatter. But it runs.
And you?
How are you running after last night?
You heard about that?
I think the whole town heard about that.
Is that from the game or the fight?
I'm not sure. It's all blurred
into one big beating.
The good news is,
you guys got into a rhythm...
...apart from that vomiting thing,
which was on Sports Center.
Oh, God.
After that, the team was really clicking.
Yeah, it was starting to come together.
Yeah.
-You want to sit down?
-No, I should go.
Thanks for coming by.
-Wow. Ow.
-What?
Oh! Ow!
Jesus!
-It looks worse than it feels.
-It looks like hell.
-Then it looks exactly like it feels.
-Here.
Wild yam?
Yeah.
Don't laugh, it works.
It's great for sore muscles and bruises.
-I use it all the time.
-You don't have to do that.
Will you put it on? You can barely move.
This will be a little bit...
-Cold!
-Sorry, sorry.
Here, your shoulders.
Better?
Better.
You're the first player I can remember...
...who cares more about his teammates
than himself.
That's something this team's been
missing for a really long time.
It's a good thing you did last night.
It was just stupid.
Thanks.
-I'm gonna be late for work.
-Practice?
No, actually, I have work.
We only make $50 a game.
Gotta pay the bills, right?
Mac's, down on A Street.
Come in, I'll buy you a beer.
All right, I'll do that.
Keep putting that yam on.
Guys!
You gotta be kidding.
I didn't park in your space.
No, no.
But, unfortunately,
you did park in Lamont's space.
-He's not nearly as lenient as I am.
-On three, fellas.
-We got this. We got this.
-You want to put the car back?
This is none of your business.
Shane is our business.
-We're the guards.
-And we protect our quarterback.
This is funny to them bozos.
You got a joke? You got a joke?
That's your ride right there, ain't it?
Yeah.
That's my windshield!
-Now, put the car back.
-Son of a bitch!
Son of a...
Oh, son of a bitch? I'm a son of a bitch?
Stop, stop!
Come on, goddamn it, help me!
You're gonna pay for this!
No, I'm not. Stop messing
with my man, that includes his ride.
And wax that motherfucker.
Give it a tune-up, too.
Ready to go to practice?
Yeah, let's do that.
-How's that arm?
-Good.
What's that smell?
Wild yam.
-That's nice.
-You like that?
And so, boys and girls,
if anybody does have any firearms...
...you need to turn them in
as soon as possible.
No questions asked.
Understood?
All right.
Okay, coach, it's all yours.
Last Sunday, I saw a team on the field
play as hard as they could...
...to win the football game.
We lost. Not because of effort or desire...
...but because of lack of leadership
and trust. One's been resolved.
But leadership means nothing
if a team doesn't believe in each other.
Players spend years together
before they develop trust.
I'm asking you to do it in a week,
not a reasonable request, but...
...these aren't reasonable times.
I know you all have concerns
about this Sunday.
But a real man...
...admits his fears.
I'm asking you to do that here, tonight.
Who wants to start?
Let's talk about fears.
Fears.
I'm scared of spiders, coach.
-That's not what I meant.
-I'm afraid of spiders, too.
Goddamn spiders freak me, too, fellas.
Well, I didn't mean that.
Ever get one of those spiders
crawling up your arm?
-Crawling on you?
-Damn!
Thanks, Jumbo. You can just
rock me to sleep tonight.
Okay, that's great, but I'm talking
about what scares us on the field.
Like spiders on the field?
Can we get beyond the spiders, please?
Bees.
Bees?
-Bees?
-Bees.
Anybody here afraid
of anything other than insects?
Come on.
Quicksand.
Shit, yeah!
Quicksand's a scary mother, man.
It sucks you right in and even
if you scream, you get that muck...
I don't think that's it.
That's not what he had in mind.
-What's he talking about, then?
-Ask him.
What's up, Shane?
You're playing...
...and you think everything is going fine.
But then one thing goes wrong...
...and another...
...and another.
You try to fight back, but the harder
you fight, the deeper you sink.
Until you can't move.
You can't breathe...
...because you're in over your head...
...like quicksand.
That's some deep shit.
Anything else you're afraid of?
-Going back to the mini-mart.
-The shipping yard.
The auto plant.
Prison.
Yeah, all right.
The truth is,
you guys have been given something...
...that every athlete dreams of:
A second chance.
And you're afraid of blowing it.
We all are.
But now our fear is shared
and we can overcome it together.
Let's lose that fear this Sunday
and put it into San Diego!
Come on!
Another vicious hit
by the All-Pro Hank Morris.
That's his third of the game.
It's just me, dickhead.
I tell you,
he is really putting a hurt on Falco.
I'm not sure how much more
of this abuse he can take.
Huddle up!
Same play, except let Morris by.
Nobody touch him.
-It's 16-0 already.
-I said let him through!
Get some penetration, Morris!
Get some penetration!
Blue 88!
Now, that is a hit!
Holy shit!
Let's haul ass, round boy!
Follow me! Follow me!
Holy shit!
Go!
Jump on his back!
Here it comes! I'm coming through!
Fumiko scores!
I love to see a fat guy score!
Why?
Because you get a fat-guy spike,
and then you get a fat-guy dance.
Pork rice!
That's not in the playbook.
Yeah.
Maybe we should put it in.
Kick-off!
So, Annabelle, what do you, like,
think of our friends?
I think...
...they're friendly.
I know! Aren't they?
Yeah.
We'll stretch them right here.
Green 95!
Green...
...95!
What the hell?
Start the ball! Get the ball off!
Hold the play clock.
Start the ball on the play clock.
False start on the offense.
Number 72, Number 77, Number 60...
...Number 61, Number 87 and Number 53.
Five yards.
Still first down.
That's bullshit! The one girl slapped
the other girl on the ass, Jimmy.
You're killing me!
You want to see mine?
I got something for you.
-Here we go.
-Don't throw it!
Damn it! They did it again!
Ray Smith with the interception.
First down, Washington.
-Nice going!
-You're killing me!
-Defense, get out there!
-Iet's go.
Stop her from shaking her ass
for two minutes!
98 Shake.
98 Shake!
Green 99!
Not bad, Falco.
Touchdown, Brian Murphy.
Everybody in the stadium knows
that an onside kick is coming...
...with 55 seconds left on the clock.
With just 55 seconds left,
Washington has to recover the ball...
...call a time-out fast, so Gruff
will have a shot at a field goal.
Big Bateman ends up with the ball!
Danny, go down!
No one's gonna tackle him.
He's reversing his field!
He's forgot the clock's running out.
Well, he's trying to run out the clock.
Danny, go down!
You're using up the clock!
You won't see that every day.
Time out! Time out!
Nice hit, Shane!
What do you think?
We don't stop the clock, it's over.
Give me a chance, I'm bored.
You're looking at a 65-yard field goal.
You just hold it,
and I'll kick the bloody piss out of it.
What the hell?
What the hell!
Field goal!
McGinty's gonna let Gruff
try this field goal from 65 yards out!
I don't know if he has enough leg.
I think he's smoking on the field.
Smoking? I'm sure you just imagined that.
No, I saw the smoke and everything.
Vito! Look who's on TV!
He wants to keep his pub,
he's gonna stop blowing some kicks!
I'm telling you, that's him.
It's straight enough.
lf it's got the distance...
It has the distance! It's good!
Washington wins!
The 65-yard field-goal attempt
is good by Nigel Gruff.
Final score: Washington 17, San Diego 16.
-You're the man!
-Oh, bollocks!
Come here!
Sorry, man. Sorry, excuse me.
All right. Good game.
We snuck by on that one.
-I'll take it.
-All right.
I'll take it. Congrats.
-What do you think of the new team?
-It's great!
These guys are like us.
This strike ain't about guys like me.
It's about them superstars...
...who want $8 million
instead of $7 million. To hell with them.
This is the most fun I've had
in football in years. Go Falco!
All right. Let's go, baby, let's go!
-I love you, Annabelle.
-I know you do, Alan. We're closed.
Oh, hey!
-You can come in.
-Come on in, buddy!
You go.
Out, out!
You're Shane Falco.
-Way to go. You guys kick ass!
-Thanks.
-Way to go.
-Bye! Take care.
Hi.
Sure it's okay? I don't want to get you
in trouble with your boss.
No, she won't mind.
Come on in. You want a beer?
Sure.
We were so tight.
We had so much fun in here.
Since I was five years old,
I've been sitting on those stools.
And then after he died, I took over.
Is that you and him?
Yeah.
He was the biggest Washington fan
you have ever seen.
Other kids got bedtime stories,
I got football stories.
He used to talk all the time...
...about the glory days of football.
Said how they were...
...gone forever.
I wish he was here to see you guys play.
-I don't know about that.
-I do.
Good game today.
Thanks.
It's late.
Yeah.
Us babies need our rest.
Yeah, you do.
I'm sorry, but between the guys
on the field...
...and the guys in the bar,
a girI's gotta keep her guard up.
Yeah, I imagine.
Yeah.
You coming to the game on Sunday?
No, we don't travel with the team.
Can I see you when I get back?
Sure.
Good night, Annabelle.
Good night.
-What do you do here, John?
-You go for it. You have to.
But Falco's been shut down
by this defense all afternoon.
But I'll tell you this, all it takes...
...is one big play to get him back
in the ball game.
And here goes Falco.
Falco scores! Falco scores!
Here's Falco. He'll try to reverse pivot,
turn and pitch out here.
But in doing so, his left guard,
André Jackson, is going to pull...
...and Falco will hit him
with the ball in the back.
Then it's gonna flop around the ground.
Here comes Cochran, he'll kick it.
Franklin's gonna pick it up.
Franklin's gonna get hit right here.
The ball will go flying in the air.
Falco will pick it up...
...and the guy who started the play, Falco...
...will end up with it
in the end zone for a touchdown!
-Welcome to strike football.
-And the fabulous Falco.
If they can win against Dallas...
...they'll do what Washington
hasn't done in over seven years:
Get to the playoffs.
Call time out! Time out!
Time out!
Time out Washington.
Franklin, come here, come here, come on.
I thought I had it...
Shut up. Give me the Stick 'em.
-That's illegal.
-Think you'll go to football jail?
Now, you know this don't look natural.
Don't talk. We'll run the same play.
You'll catch the ball.
I look like I just jacked off an elephant!
Say you understand.
I understand.
Go out there and catch the ball
for a change, all right?
Damn! This cup is stuck!
Gonna need some time on this one.
Here we go. Same play.
Pro Right, Switch 9...
Franklin!
I can't get the damn cup off!
You can do this.
It's one on one. Ready?
Ready!
Blue 89!
Franklin catches the ball!
Who would've thought?
He never catches a ball.
But he caught the ball!
That makes the score 21 to 20.
Conventional wisdom says
kick the extra point, tie the game...
...and go into overtime.
Especially with the playoffs on the line.
But Jimmy McGinty is anything
but a conventional guy.
And McGinty says, "Go for it."
Let's go for the win!
I need a receiver!
4-22 Y Cross, okay? We gotta have it!
Ready? Go! Ready!
This kind of situation has not been
Falco's strong point in the past.
Falco rolls to his left and throws...
...right into the defender's hands.
And he drops it right into the unsure hands
of Clifford Franklin!
Washington wins!
What a lucky break for Shane Falco,
who threw a bad pass...
...that could've blown the game
for Washington.
Get over it.
It's a win.
Better lucky than good?
Right.
Shane Falco.
-Great game out there today.
-Thanks.
To what do you attribute this team's
sudden rise over these past few weeks?
You know, you should talk to Franklin.
He's the hero today.
Clifford Franklin. Terrific day today.
Yeah, today was a good day
for Clifford Franklin.
Clifford Franklin can't wait till tomorrow.
Clifford Franklin gets better looking
every day.
We're beginning to scratch the surface
of the talents of Clifford Franklin.
Clifford Franklin has moves even
Clifford Franklin ain't seen yet.
You showed us a few moves
today against Phoenix...
...but it could be a different story
against Dallas.
That's the same story, different chapter.
The football is like a one-man cold
to Clifford Franklin.
Clifford Franklin's the only one catching it
and coming down with it.
Cheers, babe.
I think we got it.
To victory!
Feels good, doesn't it?
One game away from the playoffs?
And the hunt? That ring's so close
you can almost feel it on your finger.
-What are you up to?
-What?
I can't get excited about the future
of my team?
Okay, I got some great news.
Martel and Carr have crossed
the picket line.
With the deal I made them swallow,
I can't afford not to take them back.
No.
No what?
I'm sticking with Falco.
Jimmy, come on.
Have you read the newspaper?
The entire Dallas team
has crossed the picket line.
Thanksgiving night
we play the world champions.
We have a deal.
No interference with my coaching.
As long as the strike is on,
Falco is my quarterback.
We have to beat Dallas
to get into the playoffs.
Falco can't do that.
You saw what happened yesterday.
Jesus Christ!
Do you think he'll have
that luck against Dallas, too?
-They'll murder him!
-He's just getting his game back.
He falls apart
whenever the game is on the line!
That's been his rap
ever since the Sugar Bowl.
There are 21 other guys
who put their faith in you to lead them.
They'd be heartbroken
if you abandoned them...
...before the biggest game of their lives.
You really are a son of a bitch,
you know that?
What are you doing?
I don't want to make
the same mistake I did in Phoenix.
We might end up
in that situation with Dallas.
They like to send their safeties...
...put the pressure on.
Yeah, coach?
It's over.
Martel crossed.
I'm sorry.
"Chokes with the game on the line."
ls that what O'Neil said?
It's okay.
It's better for the team, right?
I mean, Martel...
...he is the best. The guy's got it all.
No.
He doesn't have heart.
You do.
It's been a privilege.
Thanks for believing.
You give them hell on Thursday.
I just wanted to tell you before you left...
I'm sorry.
-Thanks.
-No, really.
I think it's terrible
what they do to you guys.
They make you believe
that you're better than you really are.
Then they pull the rug out from under you.
The cruelest thing
that they can give guys like you...
...is hope.
You're a real class act, Martel...
...a real class act.
She deserves better.
You're a sinking ship.
Don't drag her down with you.
Take care of my guys.
Come on, boys, let's go!
Nothing but water left in here. Let's go.
I have a date.
-But I love you, Annabelle.
-I know you do, Alan.
'Bye, you guys. Be careful!
Here he is!
Ladies and gentlemen...
...Number 16 in your programs...
...Number 1 in your hearts!
Shane Falco!
Falco! Falco!
Cheers. God bless you.
-Cheers.
Are you all right?
I'm done.
What?
Martel crossed.
Bloody hell.
When will you tell the guys?
-I don't want to ruin...
-No, no, wait.
Cut that music! Cut it!
Turn the music off! Cut it!
Shane's got something to tell you.
I've got good news.
This Thursday you'll be with
the best quarterback in the league.
Damn right.
Martel.
He crossed.
Martel crossed.
While you guys are getting pounded
by Dallas...
...just kidding...
...I'll be drinking beer on my boat.
Kicking back.
Sentinels...
...raise your glasses.
This is to Shane Falco.
He's our quarterback.
He's our leader.
But most of all, he's our friend.
This is for you, man.
To Falco!
Thanks.
It's been fun.
Welcome back to Nextel Stadium
in our nation's capital.
I'm Pat Summerall and with me,
as always, is John Madden.
It appears that the strike
is coming to a close.
Martel will be resuming
the quarterback position tonight.
I gotta admit, I was looking forward...
...to seeing what Falco could do
with one more game.
He made amazing progress
the past few weeks...
...under the tutelage of Jimmy McGinty.
He really did.
But tonight it'll be Martel
leading Washington against Dallas.
I never thought I'd say this, but...
...I'm gonna kind of miss
those replacement games.
Bring back Falco!
ladies and gentlemen,
leading your Washington Sentinels today...
...welcome back Number 7, Eddie Martel.
Go on, boys!
Red 21!
Come on, Martel. Get moving!
Maybe you should try scrambling.
Brilliant. How about a quick kick?
Hey, Butler.
-Red 38!
-Hey, man.
If it ain't any trouble,
I'd love to get your autograph after.
You want it, you got it, scab!
All right.
Cochran fumbles the ball, Dallas recovers.
First down and goal on the two-yard line.
Hawk 9, Stay!
Bateman! Hawk 9, Stay!
I'm back!
Touchdown, Dallas.
They're quitting on you!
Gold 41!
Pass intended
to Brian Murphy, incomplete.
Throw right, you're going left!
Right, right, right.
You went left, I want you to go right!
No, right!
Right, you idiot!
Hey, easy!
Brian Murphy fumbled the ball.
Dallas recovers.
Nice hands.
Three-two Magic, Rack Zero.
What the hell was that about?
Touchdown, Dallas.
Gruff, wake up!
What the...
Pass incomplete by Eddie Martel.
What the hell was that?
I'm talking to you!
I call the plays out on the field.
-That's not how I coach.
-I don't give a shit...
...because that's the way I play.
That's the end of the first half...
...with a score of Dallas 17, Washington 0.
Coach McGinty!
What will Washington need
to get back into this game?
-Heart.
-I'm sorry?
You've gotta have heart.
Can you elaborate?
Miles and miles of heart.
There you have it,
in a word, from Coach McGinty...
... Washington will need "heart"
to get back into this...
I ran it like you said!
You just underthrew me!
This isn't a track meet, asshole.
You have to look for the ball!
I'll pull you off the field, you spoiIt punk.
Is O'Neil gonna side with a burnout coach
or someone who puts fans in the stands?
Son of a bitch!
What are you thinking about?
We got a game to play!
-No one can beat Dallas with these losers!
-I can.
Falco, great to see you.
Now, get the hell out of my locker room!
-Coach?
-What took you so long?
Traffic.
Suit up!
What?
-O'Neil will fire your ass!
-It won't be the first time!
This is bullshit! I'll end this right now.
Come and get some!
You big fatty!
This doesn't change anything.
I'm an All-Pro quarterback!
I've got two Super Bowl rings!
You're no more than a replacement.
Yeah.
I can live with that.
My brothers, will somebody
please get this asshole out of here?
Get your hands off me, you gorilla!
Jimmy McGinty is anything
but a conventional guy.
And McGinty says, with the playoffs
on the line, "Go for it. "
Get to the playoffs.
Something Washington...
...has not been able to do
against Dallas in seven years.
Falco?
What the hell is he up to?
Look, here comes Falco! Falco's back!
What happened to Martel?
I don't know, but the way Falco's running...
...and that look he has in his eye,
he thinks he's gonna play.
I'm sorry.
They're playing zone out there
and you can pick them apart...
...if you keep your eyes open...
He seems to be necking with
that cheerleader! That's what he's doing!
Players aren't supposed to be
fraternizing with cheerleaders.
Yeah, but what are they gonna do?
Fire him?
-You give me strength.
-You're late for work.
Kick ass, Falco!
What's all the celebrating about?
We're down 17-0.
It's nasty out there.
That's why girls don't play
the game, coach.
Listen up. This time tomorrow,
the strike will be officially over.
Dallas has made a big mistake.
They haven't been afraid of you.
They should be, because you have
a powerful weapon working for you.
There is no tomorrow for you.
That makes you all very dangerous people!
Kick ass on one. Ready?
Clifford Franklin is looking for a new home.
Ready for some pain?
-Bring it on.
-It's coming.
It's coming.
See him coming in motion?
I've never seen anything like this!
Unbelievable!
There's at least five, six flags out there.
Hats, everything!
This is what you call
an old-fashioned melee.
Unnecessary roughness,
Number 16 and Number 34.
Fifteen yards, so that's, wait...
...45...30...
How many yards so far?
Who do they think they're playing here?
Let's go! Come on!
My knee!
It's my knee!
I think I broke it.
Did I do it? Did I score?
-Yeah, you did it.
-God, it hurts!
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry. Going out
in front of 80,000 people ain't bad.
You finish what you started.
White 24!
Blue 15! Hut, hut!
First down, Washington.
-Good job.
-I got skills.
-Feel like running the ball?
-Better give it to Wilkinson.
He's going to jail.
-I'll clear the way.
-I'm right behind you.
We need it!
A gain of 20 yards by Ray Smith.
First down.
I know you're tired. I know you're hurting.
I wish I could say something
classy and inspirational...
...but it wouldn't be our style.
Pain heals.
Chicks dig scars.
Glory lasts forever.
Right on, Shane.
Right on, baby!
Shotgun, DC Right.
Flip 90, Dig, on the center. Ready?
We're looking at a different team here
in the second half.
Absolutely. Washington is playing
like there's no tomorrow...
...because there isn't.
Touchdown, baby!
Son of a bitch!
Odd bullets, blitz coverage!
Daniel Bateman comes up
with the big stop on third and one.
That forces a Dallas punt.
Pat, with 28 seconds remaining,
Washington needs a decent return...
...in order to give Gruff
a shot to tie the game.
With 12 seconds remaining...
-It's yours, Nigel.
-...a 32-yard field goal...
...will send this game into overtime.
Thirty-two yards is just
a chip shot for Gruff.
Are you all right?
I'm sorry.
I had the money but I pissed it
away down the track again.
What? What are you talking about?
They'll take my pub away from me.
It's all I've got.
Come on, Shane!
It's a fake! Falco still has it!
He's running with it!
Touchdown, Falco!
Holding! Number 68 on the offense.
Ten-yard penalty. Repeat first down.
What a terrible call!
Time out!
-You okay?
-I broke my arm.
Cheers. You saved my ass.
Take care.
You'll have to explain to me
what that was about.
What's it gonna be?
I want the ball.
Winners always do.
Spread formation.
Damn!
Sorry, Shane. I'm sorry, everybody.
No problem.
Just rip someone's head off on this one.
Consider it done.
All right. So besides me,
who really wants the ball?
Yeah, you want it, Brian.
Let's hook up.
DC Left, Wide Motion, 88 War.
Gentlemen...
It's been an honor to share
the field of battle with you.
We ain't losing this game.
Green 86!
Touchdown, Brian Murphy!
I knew it! I knew it all along!
Jimmy, you beautiful son of a bitch!
I knew you could do it!
Final score: Washington 20, Dallas 17.
Washington goes to the playoffs!
You did it!
When the replacement players
for the Sentinels left the stadium...
...there was no ticker-tape parade...
...no endorsement deals for sneakers...
...or soda pop or breakfast cereal...
...just a locker to be cleaned out...
...and a ride home to catch.
But what they didn't know...
...was that their lives
would be changed forever...
...because they had been
part of something great.
And greatness, no matter how brief...
...stays with a man.
Every athlete dreams of a second chance.
These men lived it.